<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<title>Heath Anderson's Blog</title>
<link>https://www.heathanderson.net/</link>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.heathanderson.net/" />
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://www.heathanderson.net/rss.xml" />
<id>tag:heathanderson.net,2022-12-09:223457</id>
<updated>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 21:54:08 GMT</updated>


<entry>
<title>Website Redesign</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.heathanderson.net/2022/website-updated" />
<id>https://www.heathanderson.net/2022/website-updated</id>
<published>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 00:00:00 GMT</published>
<author>
<name>Heath Anderson</name>
<uri>https://www.heathanderson.net/</uri>
</author>
<content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="https://www.heathanderson.net/"><![CDATA[<p>This redesign was more about using a consistent set of technologies between the sites I maintain than anything else. Here's a list of projects and technologies that are being used in some way for this site:
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.w3.org/html/logo/">HTML5</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.w3.org/TR/CSS/">CSS3</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">Atom</a></li>
<li><a href="http://html5boilerplate.com/">HTML5 Boilerplate</a></li>
<li><a href="https://purecss.io/">Pure.css</a></li>
<li><a href="https://fontawesome.com/">Font Awesome</a></li>
<li><a href="https://gitlab.com/idotj/mastodon-embed-feed-timeline">Mastodon timeline feed</a></li>
<li><a href="https://github.com/handerson/harp-blog-example">handerson/harp-blog-example</a></li>
<li>Hosted by <a href="https://www.digitalocean.com/">Digital Ocean</a></li>
</ul>
</p>
<div class="pure-g post-columns">
<div class="pure-u-md-1-2">
<div class="post-content">
<img src="/images/posts/old-site.jpg" alt="Screen capture showing the header of the original site" class="shadow" />
<span class="caption">The first redesign in 2011.</span></div>
</div>
<div class="pure-u-md-1-2">
<div class="post-content">
<img src="/images/posts/site-design.png" alt="Screen capture showing the header of the previous design" class="shadow" />
<span class="caption">The November 2012 redesign.</span></div>
</div>
<div class="pure-u-md-1 ">
<div class="post-content">
<img src="/images/posts/new-design-2022.png" alt="Screen capture showing this site's new design" class="shadow" />
<span class="caption">December 2022 redesign. I guess 10 years is a long time, huh.</span></div>
</div>
</div>]]></content>
</entry>


<entry>
<title>Creating A Simple Blog with Harp</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.heathanderson.net/2022/simple-blog-with-harp" />
<id>https://www.heathanderson.net/2022/simple-blog-with-harp</id>
<published>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 00:00:00 GMT</published>
<author>
<name>Heath Anderson</name>
<uri>https://www.heathanderson.net/</uri>
</author>
<content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="https://www.heathanderson.net/"><![CDATA[<blockquote>Harp serves Jade, Markdown, EJS, CoffeeScript, Sass, LESS and Stylus as HTML, CSS & JavaScript—no configuration necessary. <a href="https://harpjs.com/">- harpjs.com</a></blockquote>

<p><img src="/images/posts/harp-blog-header.png" alt="Screen capture showing the header of the example blog" class="shadow" /> <a href="https://harpjs.com/">Harp</a> is a straight-forward and easy to use static site generator and server. It isn&#39;t updated very often, but it still gets the job done very well for simple sites. I recently decided to use it for some simple brochure-type sites I maintain to replace compass. When it came time to update this site, I decided to replace jekyll with harp to keep maintenance simple. The lack of any built-in blogging functionality became a minor pain point. So I made a simple test project:  <a href="https://github.com/handerson/harp-blog-example">handerson/harp-blog-example</a> with basic pagination, rss feed, and syntax highlighting. You can see a demo here: <a href="https://handerson.github.io/harp-blog-example/">https://handerson.github.io/harp-blog-example/</a>.</p>
<p><img src="/images/posts/harp-blog-footer.png" alt="Screen capture showing the footer of the example blog" class="shadow right"> The pagination is very simple. The site index shows the 3 newest posts with prev/next buttons at the bottom of the page. Beyond that there isn&#39;t so much pagination as there are previous and next buttons at the bottom of each blog post. It works for what I need, but may not be enough for all use cases. The posts/index page shows a list of all posts.</p>
<p>There is <a href="https://prismjs.com/">prism</a> for syntax highlighting, and <a href="https://picocss.com">pico.css</a> for styling. </p>
]]></content>
</entry>


<entry>
<title>Vigil App Review</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.heathanderson.net/2013/05/18/vigil-app" />
<id>https://www.heathanderson.net/2013/05/18/vigil-app</id>
<published>Sat, 18 May 2013 00:00:00 GMT</published>
<author>
<name>Heath Anderson</name>
<uri>https://www.heathanderson.net/</uri>
</author>
<content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="https://www.heathanderson.net/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/posts/vigil-app.jpeg" alt="Vigil App Screen" class="shadow" /> <a href="http://vigil-app.com">Vigil</a> is an easy-to-use, inexpensive website monitoring app for iOS. I&#39;ve been using Vigil for the past few months to monitor 16 sites. It has notified me of two separate issues during that time: a bandwidth overage for a Wordpress site and a (user managed) SSL certificate expiration. About a month ago I did receive a couple of  notifications in error, but the <a href="https://twitter.com/vigilapp">Vigil twitter account</a> did a good job of communicating the problems they were having. That is the only issue I&#39;ve encountered with the service, and it was a minor one.</p>
<p>The only feature I wish Vigil included is access to more historical data; currently only the previous hour&#39;s response time data is viewable. It would be nice to be able to see a detailed history, maybe even with an option to export the the data. They are apparently developing some kind of &quot;more detailed history view&quot; for a future version:</p>
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-conversation="none"><p>@<a href="https://twitter.com/iain">iain</a> It is not possible in the client currently, but we are working on adding more detailed history views for the next major release.</p>&mdash; Vigil App (@vigilapp) <a href="https://twitter.com/vigilapp/status/323763427564744704">April 15, 2013</a></blockquote>

<p>The thing that first caught my eye about the service was the price: $9.99 for a year of monitoring an &quot;unlimited&quot; number of websites. That is <em>extremely</em> affordable. For comparison, the cheapest plan at <a href="https://www.pingdom.com/signup/">Pingdom</a> monitors up to 10 sites for $9.95 / <strong>month</strong>. It was a no-brainer to try out, and I&#39;m extrememly glad that I did. </p>
]]></content>
</entry>


<entry>
<title>Hidden Radio Bluetooth Speaker</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.heathanderson.net/2012/12/01/hidden-radio-bluetooth-speaker" />
<id>https://www.heathanderson.net/2012/12/01/hidden-radio-bluetooth-speaker</id>
<published>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</published>
<author>
<name>Heath Anderson</name>
<uri>https://www.heathanderson.net/</uri>
</author>
<content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="https://www.heathanderson.net/"><![CDATA[<p>I didn&#8217;t get off to a great start with the Hidden Radio Bluetooth speaker. I was impatient so I tried to use it just a few minutes after plugging the speaker for its initial charge. My phone started randomly disconnecting from the speaker. This problem went away after letting the speaker charge for a couple of hours. </p>
<p>Another problem I ran into was with the twist to control mechanism. The Hidden Radio is turned on by twisting the top part of the speaker. This also increases the volume. The problem was with the base. It wouldn&#8217;t easily stay in place while turning its top. I was having to push down and turn. This didn&#8217;t work very well. </p>
<p>I eventually found that cleaning the grippy material on the base with some water completely fixed the issue. Hopefully this isn&#8217;t something that has to be done too often. </p>
<p>I have the silver colored one. I don&#8217;t really care for the plastic-aping-metal look. It looks fine, but I think I would go with black if I had the chance. </p>
<p>I am mostly using the speaker to listen to podcasts, and I have no complaints with regards to audio quality or volume. It seems roughly comparable to other speakers of it&#8217;s size. </p>
<p>The location of the micro USB port is annoying. It is on the bottom of the speaker at an odd angle. I find it difficult to both insert and remove the USB cable. This port charges the speaker. The Hidden Radio has a built in battery and is meant to be portable. I would be more likely to use it this way if the charging cable port was more accessible. </p>
<p>The brightness of the the always-on (when plugged in) indicator light is another annoyance. I do have some <a href="https://www.thinkgeek.com/product/eeb6/">light blocker stickers</a> that help the situation. I wish the light would go off or dim significantly once the speaker is charged and turned off.</p>
<p>Although I do like the simplictiy of its design, I don&#8217;t think I would pay $119 (the Kickstarter price) for it again. I would probably go cheaper with <a href="http://amzn.com/B0083UU1OO">GOgroove BlueSYNC OR3</a>, or more expensive and look at the <a href="http://amzn.com/B004E10KI8">Jawbone JAMBOX</a>. The retail price for the Hidden Radio is $149. </p>]]></content>
</entry>


<entry>
<title>Do I Really Need An iPhone Dock?</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.heathanderson.net/2012/12/01/do-i-really-need-an-iphone-dock" />
<id>https://www.heathanderson.net/2012/12/01/do-i-really-need-an-iphone-dock</id>
<published>Sat, 01 Dec 2012 00:00:00 GMT</published>
<author>
<name>Heath Anderson</name>
<uri>https://www.heathanderson.net/</uri>
</author>
<content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="https://www.heathanderson.net/"><![CDATA[<p>Probably not. But I&#8217;m still using it. </p>
<p>I&#8217;ve used the Elevation Dock with Lightning Adapter for a couple of weeks now. Using the dock for another week really hasn&#8217;t done much to improve my opinion of the gadget. </p>
<p>It is easier to put the phone in the dock than to directly plug in the lightning cable. On the other hand it is much easier to disconnect the cable than to undock the phone. I&#8217;m not sure how to weigh these two facts against each other. At best it is a wash. </p>
<p>Right now I&#8217;m mostly continuing to use the dock because I like the way it looks. I suppose I will continue to use the Elevation Dock until I either find something better or get frustrated enough with the undocking procedure to decide to go dock-less. </p>
<p>Or I may actually try some kind of adhesive to attach the dock to my night stand. That seems like a really bad idea, right? </p>]]></content>
</entry>


<entry>
<title>The Elevation Dock Lightning Adapter</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.heathanderson.net/2012/11/24/the-elevation-dock-lightning-adapter" />
<id>https://www.heathanderson.net/2012/11/24/the-elevation-dock-lightning-adapter</id>
<published>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</published>
<author>
<name>Heath Anderson</name>
<uri>https://www.heathanderson.net/</uri>
</author>
<content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="https://www.heathanderson.net/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/posts/lightning-adapter.jpg" alt="Elevation Dock Lightning Adapter" class="shadow" />Earlier this year I received my <a href="http://www.elevationlab.com/products/elevationdock-for-iphone4">Elevation Dock</a> after funding the Kickstarter. I loved it. It was the absolutely the best docking solution available. Due to its low friction connector and heft it was even easier to use than just a cable. I could drop in my phone to charge, then grab it and go. No hassles. </p>
<p>Getting the iPhone 5 kind of ruined that arrangement for me. I've been stuck charging with a plain cable (awful, I know). At least with the Lightning cable I could plug it in without having to study it to make sure I'm inserting it correctly.</p>
<p>Thankfully Elevation Lab has released a <a href="http://www.elevationlab.com/products/lightning-adapter">Lightning adapter</a>. I ordered one as soon as they were available. It arrived earlier this week. </p>
<p><img src="/images/posts/lightning-adapter-installed.jpg" alt="Elevation Dock Lightning Adapter Installed" class="shadow right" />Installing the adapter was easy enough. Luckily I had an extra Lightning cable to use with it. The adapter looks nice, and works well enough. The main problem is that Apple's Lightning connector produces too much friction to undock the phone with one hand. I now have to hold down the dock to get my phone. </p>
<p>
According to Elevation Lab:
<blockquote>
The lightning connector, like all of Apple's 30pin connectors, are higher friction than our custom 30pin connectors shipped with your docks. But with the ElevationDock's weight, just some pressure from your pinky and you can remove your phone without the base moving.
</blockquote>
</p>
<p> I had this information before ordering the adapter. In theory I could still remove the phone with one hand--all I would need to do is press down with my pinky on the dock and get the phone with my other digits. In practice I have not been able to make that work. It is a two handed affair to undock my phone. So goes one of the best features of the original Elevation Dock</p>
<p>I still like the dock. The iPhone 5 version just isn't as useful as the 4/4S one. The Lightning adapter is well made, and I don't think they could have done a better job. It is my understanding that it is currently impossible for 3rd parties to create their own versions of Apple's Lightning connector. This means that Elevation Lab has made the best possible product given the current limitations.</p>
<p>The Elevation Dock is still the best iPhone dock I have found.</p>]]></content>
</entry>


<entry>
<title>A New Look</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.heathanderson.net/2012/11/24/a-new-look" />
<id>https://www.heathanderson.net/2012/11/24/a-new-look</id>
<published>Sun, 25 Nov 2012 00:00:00 GMT</published>
<author>
<name>Heath Anderson</name>
<uri>https://www.heathanderson.net/</uri>
</author>
<content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="https://www.heathanderson.net/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/posts/old-site.jpg" alt="Old Blog Design Closeup" class="shadow" />I've finally updated my blog again. I've thrown away most of the old style and code. I needed a new look. Apparently a year ago I was a bit obsessed with <a href="http://daringfireball.net/">low contrast</a> and <a href="http://webdesignandsuch.com/apple-linen-texture-effect-web-design-trend-download-tutorial/">textures</a>. These design concepts can work wonderfully. On my site they did not. I needed a new inspiration. One was not forthcoming.</p>
<p>About a month ago I started watching <a href="http://www.usanetwork.com/series/whitecollar/">White Collar</a>. I really liked the <a href="http://fr.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fichier:White_Collar_2009_logo.svg">logo</a>. It stuck with me. Last Friday I had a day off, so I decided to see if I was indeed "inspired". I suppose I was close enough. I am much happier with the current site design than the old one.</p>
<p><img src="/images/posts/site-design.png" alt="Blog Design Closeup" class="shadow right" />The rest of this paragraph may sound pretentious, and I apologize for that; however, I hope it gives some insight into the new design. The basic design language is that of a blue background overlain with a white sheet of material. The header and footer are on peeking out of the background. The blue headings and the date boxes are carved out of the white foreground to reveal the blue underneath. The white lettering in the header, footer, and date boxes are meant to be leftovers from white foreground material. The black text and images in the body of the page are sitting on top of the white foreground. </p>
<p>I also can't help but try out some new (to me) technologies, especially if they might be useful in my day job. I've used a bit of <a href="http://sass-lang.com/">Sass</a> in the context of <a href="http://www.rubyinside.com/rails-3-1-adopts-coffeescript-jquery-sass-and-controversy-4669.html">Rails</a> before, but I was interested in learning more about it. And this <a href="http://compass-style.org/">Compass</a> thing I kept hearing about sounded really useful.</p>
<p>It turns out that I really like Sass and Compass. Together they give a front-end developer many wondrous tools. It would be hard to go back to not using variables and mixins. I also found <a href="http://susy.oddbird.net/">Susy</a>, a responsive grid framework, to be very useful. </a></p>
<p>Integrating Jekyll and Sass was not as easy as I had hoped. I at first tried the <a href="https://github.com/noct/jekyll-sass">jeklyy-sass</a> gem. I could not get it work after about half an hour of futzing with it. I assume this failing was on my part, not that of the gem. I think decided to do something a bit more simple. I followed the <a href="http://martinciu.com/2011/06/blogging-like-a-hacker-using-jekyll-compass-and-foreman.html">advice</a> of another blog and just used the Jekyll and Compass command separately with <a href="http://ddollar.github.com/foreman/">foreman</a> gluing them together.</p>
<p>I also took the opportunity to research fonts/typefaces to use. All really knew was that I wanted a strong sans serif font for the headings and a nice readable serif font for the body text. I did find two fonts that I really liked:
<ul>
<li><a href="http://fontdeck.com/font/groteskurw/regular">Grotesk URW</a></li>
<li><a href="http://fontdeck.com/font/skolar/regular">Skolar</a></li>
</ul>
Eventually I decided that it really didn't make sense to pay for fonts on a blog that no one actually reads. So I decided to look up what fonts are <a href="http://www.ampsoft.net/webdesign-l/WindowsMacFonts.html">installed by default</a> and pick the my favorites (as it were). I landed on Verdana for the headings and Georgia for the body.
</p>
<p>I did wind up using one custom font: <a href="http://levien.com/type/myfonts/inconsolata.html">Inconsolata</a>. I use this font in my text editor, so I decided to make the code snippets on my site use it. I found Font Squirrel's <a href="http://www.fontsquirrel.com/fontface/generator">@font-face generator</a> very useful</p>
<p> I couldn't figure out how to display each post's date until I stumbled across this post about <a href="http://snook.ca/archives/html_and_css/css-text-rotation">CSS text rotation</a>. I also had to <a href="http://www.alistapart.com/articles/understanding-css3-transitions/">brush up on CSS3 transitions</a> to create the header. Making text look indented (or a letterpress effect) with CSS is surprisingly difficult. I found this <a href="https://gist.github.com/1609945">gist</a> incredibly useful.</p>
<p>I'm still not done. There are still some bugs especially on mobile devices. I will continue to refine and fix. Hopefully this version lasts longer than a year.</p>]]></content>
</entry>


<entry>
<title>Adding a Splash Screen For An Android PhoneGap App</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.heathanderson.net/2012/03/08/adding-a-splash-screen-for-an-android-phonegap-app" />
<id>https://www.heathanderson.net/2012/03/08/adding-a-splash-screen-for-an-android-phonegap-app</id>
<published>Thu, 08 Mar 2012 00:00:00 GMT</published>
<author>
<name>Heath Anderson</name>
<uri>https://www.heathanderson.net/</uri>
</author>
<content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="https://www.heathanderson.net/"><![CDATA[<p>The fact that you can add a splash screen to your PhoneGap app on the Android platform is surprisingly hard to come across. After some searching I did find some answers. </p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://html5help.wordpress.com/2011/10/18/creating-splash-screen-start-up-screen-for-android-app-using-phonegap-jqtouch/">Adding the splash screen</a> - <a href="http://html5help.wordpress.com/">HTML5 Help</a> Blog
<li><a href="https://groups.google.com/d/msg/phonegap/lu3p_QO3Nqg/xentHyA8Pz8J">Adding a delay so in case you want force your users to wait before they use your app</a> - Google Groups
</ul>
After finding those helpful posts my next question was:
<h4>What is this property thing I'm setting?</h4>
<p>Starting on line 100 of the <a href="https://github.com/cordova/cordova-android/blob/bf693627090ee136556a4e82ed7cb0a584ff278e/framework/src/org/apache/cordova/DroidGap.java">DroidGap.java</a> file there are some helpful comments:</p>
<pre><code class="language-java">
/* Properties: The application can be configured using the following properties:
*
*    // Display a native loading dialog.  Format for value = "Title,Message".
*    // (String - default=null)
*    super.setStringProperty("loadingDialog", "Wait,Loading Demo...");
*
*    // Hide loadingDialog when page loaded instead of when deviceready event
*    // occurs. (Boolean - default=false)
*    super.setBooleanProperty("hideLoadingDialogOnPage", true);
*
*    // Cause all links on web page to be loaded into existing web view,
*    // instead of being loaded into new browser. (Boolean - default=false)
*    super.setBooleanProperty("loadInWebView", true);
*
*    // Load a splash screen image from the resource drawable directory.
*    // (Integer - default=0)
*    super.setIntegerProperty("splashscreen", R.drawable.splash);
*
*    // Time in msec to wait before triggering a timeout error when loading
*    // with super.loadUrl().  (Integer - default=20000)
*    super.setIntegerProperty("loadUrlTimeoutValue", 60000);
*
*    // URL to load if there's an error loading specified URL with loadUrl().
*    // Should be a local URL starting with file://. (String - default=null)
*    super.setStringProperty("errorUrl", "file:///android_asset/www/error.html");
*
*    // Enable app to keep running in background. (Boolean - default=true)
*    super.setBooleanProperty("keepRunning", false);
*/
</code></pre>
<p>These properties can be set in your appname.java file:</p>
<pre><code class="language-java">
package com.example.appname;
import android.app.Activity;
import android.os.Bundle;
import com.phonegap.*;
public class appname extends DroidGap
{
@Override
public void onCreate(Bundle savedInstanceState)
{
super.onCreate(savedInstanceState);
super.setIntegerProperty("splashscreen", R.drawable.splash);
super.loadUrl("file:///android_asset/www/index.html", 3000);
}
}
</code></pre>]]></content>
</entry>


<entry>
<title>My Favorite Mac OS X Apps For Web Development</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.heathanderson.net/2011/09/26/my-favorite-mac-os-x-apps-for-web-development" />
<id>https://www.heathanderson.net/2011/09/26/my-favorite-mac-os-x-apps-for-web-development</id>
<published>Mon, 26 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</published>
<author>
<name>Heath Anderson</name>
<uri>https://www.heathanderson.net/</uri>
</author>
<content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="https://www.heathanderson.net/"><![CDATA[<h4>Text Editors</h4>
<h5><a href="http://www.sublimetext.com/2">Sublime Text 2</a> (currently free; will be $59)</h5>
<p>I've been using this as my main text editor (replacing TextMate). It uses TextMate bundles and themes. Sublime runs on Mac OS X, Linux and Windows. Also checkout the Vintage mode if Vim intrigues you</p>
<h5><a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/tincta/id448340648?mt=12">Tincta</a> (free)</h5>
<p>A really simple code editor with syntax highlighting.</p>
<h4>Graphics/Design</h4>
<h5><a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/pixelmator/id407963104?mt=12">Pixelmator</a> ($29.99)</h5>
<p>I love this app. Does almost everything that Photoshop does. It actually will open Photoshop files and does a pretty good (but not perfect) job with them.</p>
<h5><a href="http://fructivity.com/">Color Picker Pro</a> (free)</h5>
<p>A simple, intuitive app that makes sampling any color on your screen super easy.</p>
<h5><a href="http://seashore.sourceforge.net/The_Seashore_Project/About.html">SeaShore</a> (free)</h5>
<p>It is literally a prettied-up, simplified version of GIMP for Mac OS X.</p>
<h4>Utilities</h4>
<h5><a href="http://mac.github.com/">GitHub for Mac</a> (free)</h5>
<p>A very nice looking Git client.</p>
<h5><a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/liya/id455484422?mt=12">Liya</a> (free) </h5>
<p>A simple GUI for MySQL, SQLite, and PostgreSQL</p>
<h5><a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/alfred/id405843582?mt=12">Alfed</a> (free)</h5>
<p>This is basically a better Spotlight. I have it mapped to Command-Space instead of Spotlight.</p>
<h5><a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/pandabar-pandora-radio-player/id459351174?mt=12">PandaBar</a> ($4.99)</h5>
<p>An awesome Pandora player.</p>
<h5><a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/divvy/id413857545?mt=12">Divvy</a> ($13.99)</h5>
<p>Manage your windows. Definitely set some global shortcuts. Mine are: &#8997;-&#8984;-f (fullscreen), &#8997;-&#8984;-&#8592; (left half of the screen), &#8997;-&#8984;-&#8594; (right half of the screen), &#8997;-&#8984;-&#8593; (top half of the screen), &#8997;-&#8984;-&#8595; (bottom half of the screen)</p>]]></content>
</entry>


<entry>
<title>Candy Japan</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.heathanderson.net/2011/09/26/candy-japan" />
<id>https://www.heathanderson.net/2011/09/26/candy-japan</id>
<published>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 00:00:00 GMT</published>
<author>
<name>Heath Anderson</name>
<uri>https://www.heathanderson.net/</uri>
</author>
<content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="https://www.heathanderson.net/"><![CDATA[<p>I just ate some weird Japanese candy called takoyaki-ya san. It is supposed to mimic the look of "octopus balls" (a Japanese dish that is decidedly not candy like). The candy, unlike the food on which it is based, is peach/strawberry flavored. Takoyaki-ya san embodies two concepts that seem a bit odd to me: candy that looks like real (non-candy) food and candy that you have to assemble yourself. Overall it was pretty ok. The texture was strange, but the flavor was fine.</p>
<p>I received this candy from <a href="http://www.candyjapan.com/">CandyJapan.com</a>--a neat little service that will send you some weird Japanese candy twice a month for $24. I don't know how long I'll keep my subscription, but I think I'll get at least a few months of entertainment out it</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/m0BF4cNGLA0?wmode=opaque" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>]]></content>
</entry>


<entry>
<title>Some Simple jQuery Plugins</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.heathanderson.net/2011/08/27/s-jquery-plugins" />
<id>https://www.heathanderson.net/2011/08/27/s-jquery-plugins</id>
<published>Sat, 27 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</published>
<author>
<name>Heath Anderson</name>
<uri>https://www.heathanderson.net/</uri>
</author>
<content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="https://www.heathanderson.net/"><![CDATA[<p>Below are some really simple jQuery plugins that I've thrown together over the past couple of years that I've found useful.</p>
<p>Need to scroll to element with animation? Here you go:</p>
<pre><code class="language-javascript">
// scroll to animation
// example usage: $('.scroll_to_here').scrollTo();
jQuery.fn.scrollTo = function(speed) {
if(speed === undefined ){
speed = 'slow';
}
$('html,body').animate({scrollTop: this.offset().top},speed);
};
</code></pre>
<p>Ajax polling is pretty easy with jQuery, but it is nice to have reusable function so you don't repeat yourself. The plugin below is based on another <a href="http://www.nickriggs.com/posts/simple-ajax-polling-plugin-for-jquery/">simple ajax polling plugin</a> that scales the amount of time between requests. This plugin uses a simple interval with a maximum number of attempts. </p>
<pre><code class="language-javascript">
//Simple AJAX Polling jQuery Plugin
// example usage:
/* $.ajaxPoll({
url: "/path",
type: "GET",
interval: 250,
maxAttempts: 25,
successCondition: function(result) {
return result != "processing";
},
success: function(data) {
$('#container').replaceWith(data);
}
});
*/
jQuery.ajaxPoll = function(user_options){
var options = {
interval: 30000,
maxAttempts: 15
}
jQuery.extend(options, user_options);
var attempts = 0;
options.success = function(data, status) {
if (options.successCondition(data)) {
if (options.successCallback){
options.successCallback(data, status);
}
return;
}
attempts++;
if (attempts > options.maxAttempts) {
return;
}
setTimeout(function() { jQuery.ajax(options) }, options.interval);
};
jQuery.ajax(options);
}
</code></pre>
<p>The HTML5 placeholder attribute is awesome, but some browsers (IE and ... maybe just IE?) do not support it. Here is a jQuery plugin that solves that problem by clearing and restoring a field's placeholder value in browsers that don't handle that silliness for you.</p>
<pre><code class="language-javascript">
// clears and restores a field's default value
// example usage (js): $('input.has_default').hasDefaultValue();
// example usage (html): <input class="has_default" placeholder="This is displayed by default" type="text"/>
jQuery.fn.hasDefaultValue = function() {
function supports_input_placeholder() {
var i = document.createElement('input');
return 'placeholder' in i;
}
if(!supports_input_placeholder()){
this.each(function(){
if(this.value === ""){
this.value = $(this).attr("placeholder")
}
});
this.focus(function(event){
if(this.value === $(this).attr("placeholder")){
this.value = ""
}
})
this.blur(function(event){
if($(this).attr("placeholder") && this.value === ""){
this.value = $(this).attr("placeholder");
}
})
}
};
</code></pre>]]></content>
</entry>


<entry>
<title>Roku 2</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.heathanderson.net/2011/08/27/roku-2" />
<id>https://www.heathanderson.net/2011/08/27/roku-2</id>
<published>Sat, 27 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</published>
<author>
<name>Heath Anderson</name>
<uri>https://www.heathanderson.net/</uri>
</author>
<content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="https://www.heathanderson.net/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/posts/roku_box.jpg" alt="Roku 2 Box" class="shadow" />One month ago I got a <a href="http://www.roku.com/">Roku 2</a>. This was my fourth Roku. I bought a first generation Roku in June 2009 and I loved it. I eventually bought one for every TV in my house. My third box was the second generation Roku 1. It was much smaller than the first gen, had a better remote, and also had a cool little fabric tag on it. The Roku 2 follows in the second gen Roku 1's footsteps by being even smaller, having an even better remote, and still having the little purple tag.</p>
<p>A new feature of the Roku 2 is the ability to play games. The only game that I've tried is the included Angry Birds. It's a good version of the game, and the motion controls are surprisingly good. But, for me, gaming on the Roku is just a nice secondary feature. I think I'll stick to either my Xbox, Playstation or Wii for the majority of game playing.</p>
<img src="/images/posts/roku_in_box.jpg" alt="The Roku 2 is small" class="shadow" />
<p>The best thing about the Roku is the number of 'channels' available.  There is one for <a href="http://www.netflix.com">Netflix</a>, <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Instant-Video/b/ref=sa_menu_aiv_vid0?ie=UTF8&node=2858778011">Amazon Instant Video</a>, <a href="http://www.hulu.com">Hulu</a>, and <a href="http://www.roku.com/roku-channel-store">many more</a>. The first generation boxes seem to have some trouble with channels like Hulu that sport a flashy interface. The Roku 2 doesn't have this problem. This is definitely the best Roku yet.</p>]]></content>
</entry>


<entry>
<title>Minimalist Business Card</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.heathanderson.net/2011/08/22/minimalist-business-card" />
<id>https://www.heathanderson.net/2011/08/22/minimalist-business-card</id>
<published>Mon, 22 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</published>
<author>
<name>Heath Anderson</name>
<uri>https://www.heathanderson.net/</uri>
</author>
<content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="https://www.heathanderson.net/"><![CDATA[<p><img class="shadow" src="/images/posts/borismus_business_card.png" alt="Boris Smus' Business Card" /> I came across the <a href="http://smus.com/minimal-business-card-design">business card</a> to the left via <a href="http://boingboing.net/2011/08/22/ultraminimalist-business-card.html">Boing Boing</a>. Even though the original post is over one year old, it inspired me to try to design a simple business card (although I suppose it is more of a calling card). Graphic design is one of my weaker skills so I like to practice when I can. My take on the concept is below: </p>
<img src="/images/posts/card.png" class="shadow" alt="My Business Card" />
<p>I kind of like it. I ordered twenty from <a href="http://www.zazzle.com/">Zazzle</a> for $7 just to see what they look like printed on actual paper.</p>]]></content>
</entry>


<entry>
<title>Bastion</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.heathanderson.net/2011/08/21/bastion" />
<id>https://www.heathanderson.net/2011/08/21/bastion</id>
<published>Sun, 21 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</published>
<author>
<name>Heath Anderson</name>
<uri>https://www.heathanderson.net/</uri>
</author>
<content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="https://www.heathanderson.net/"><![CDATA[<p><img class="shadow" src="/images/posts/bastion/bastion_1.jpg" alt="Bastion Screenshot"/>I've been playing <a href="http://supergiantgames.com/">Bastion</a> for the Xbox 360. I love this game. The art is great, the dynamic narration is unlike anything I've ever seen in a game before, and the music is amazing. The game narrates the main character's actions while you play--a feature that would certainly be annoying if poorly executed. Luckily here it is wonderfully done. The narrator simultaneously injects both humor and a sense of weight to the story. The music is great and evocative. I even <a href="http://supergiantgames.bandcamp.com/">bought</a> the soundtrack.</p>
<img class="shadow" src="/images/posts/bastion/bastion_2.jpg" alt="Bastion Screenshot"/>
<p>And on top of all that the game is really fun. Every weapon featured in the game is fun, looks cool and is useful. I'm starting my second play through and I'm looking forward to experimenting with some of the weapons that I only briefly used on my first try.</p>
<p>Bastion is one of the best games I've played this year. If you have a 360 <a href="http://marketplace.xbox.com/en-US/Product/Bastion/66acd000-77fe-1000-9115-d80258410b66">download</a> the Bastion demo and give it a try. </p>
<object style="height: 366px; width: 640px"><param name="movie" value="http://www.youtube.com/v/TptJHeWngJs?version=3"><param name="allowFullScreen" value="true"><param name="allowScriptAccess" value="always"><embed src="http://www.youtube.com/v/TptJHeWngJs?version=3" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" allowfullscreen="true" wmode="opaque"  allowScriptAccess="always" width="600" height="366"></object>]]></content>
</entry>


<entry>
<title>Automating New Post Creation in Jekyll</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.heathanderson.net/2011/08/14/1-automating-new-post-creation-in-jekyll" />
<id>https://www.heathanderson.net/2011/08/14/1-automating-new-post-creation-in-jekyll</id>
<published>Sun, 14 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</published>
<author>
<name>Heath Anderson</name>
<uri>https://www.heathanderson.net/</uri>
</author>
<content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="https://www.heathanderson.net/"><![CDATA[<p>After automating deployment, my next goal was to automate creating a new post. After looking around a bit I decided to slightly modify the rake task used by <a href="https://github.com/imathis/octopress">Octopress</a>, a Jekyll based blogging framework. </p>
<pre><code class="language-ruby">
# adapted from https://github.com/imathis/octopress/blob/master/Rakefile
# usage rake new_post['My New Post'] or rake new_post (defaults to "My New Post")
desc "Start a new post"
task :new_post, :title do |t, args|
args.with_defaults(:title => 'My New Post')
title = args.title
filename = "_posts/#{Time.now.strftime('%Y-%m-%d')}-#{title.downcase.gsub(/&/,'and').gsub(/[,'":\?!\(\)\[\]]/,'').gsub(/[\W\.]/, '-').gsub(/-+$/,'')}.html"
puts "Creating new post: #{filename}"
open(filename, 'w') do |post|
system "mkdir -p _posts";
post.puts "---"
post.puts "layout: post"
post.puts "title: \"#{title.gsub(/&/,'&amp;')}\""
post.puts "date: #{Time.now.strftime('%Y-%m-%d %H:%M')}"
post.puts "published: false"
post.puts "---"
end
end
</code></pre>
<p>Now that the above is in my <a href="https://github.com/handerson/heathanderson.net/blob/master/rakefile.rb">rakefile</a>, I'm just a <code>rake new_post['This is Awesome']</code> away from starting a new post.]]></content>
</entry>


<entry>
<title>Deploying a Jekyll Site to Amazon S3</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.heathanderson.net/2011/08/14/0-deploying-jekyll" />
<id>https://www.heathanderson.net/2011/08/14/0-deploying-jekyll</id>
<published>Sun, 14 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</published>
<author>
<name>Heath Anderson</name>
<uri>https://www.heathanderson.net/</uri>
</author>
<content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="https://www.heathanderson.net/"><![CDATA[<p>Before moving my blog to Amazon S3 I wanted to make sure that I could deploy updates easily. I came across several ways to do it. The easiest method I found was in a <a href="http://blog.hendrikvolkmer.de/2011/02/25/moving-from-wordpress-on-a-vps-to-jekyll-and-amazon-s3/">blog post</a> by <a href="http://blog.hendrikvolkmer.de/about/">Hendrik Volkmer</a>. It uses a command line tool called <code>s3cmd</code> run through a rake task. <a href="http://s3tools.org/s3cmd">s3cmd</a> can be installed using <a href="http://mxcl.github.com/homebrew/">Homebrew</a> on Mac OS X. </p>
<pre><code class="language-bash">
brew install s3cmd
</code></pre>
<p>I updated the rake task to use S3's reduced <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2010/05/19/announcing-amazon-s3-reduced-redundancy-storage/">redundancy storage</a> and set an <a href="https://developer.yahoo.com/performance/rules.html#expires">Expires header</a> for my images by using s3cmd's <code>--reduced-redundancy</code>, <code>--exclude</code>, and <code>--add-header</code> options. You can find out about other <code>s3smd</code> options on the <a href="http://s3tools.org/s3cmd-sync">s3tools website</a>.</p>
<pre><code class="language-ruby">
# based on http://blog.hendrikvolkmer.de/2011/02/25/moving-from-wordpress-on-a-vps-to-jekyll-and-amazon-s3/
task :default => :deploy
desc "Deploy to S3"
task :deploy do
sh "jekyll"
sh "s3cmd sync --reduced-redundancy --exclude 'images/*' _site/* s3://www.heathanderson.net"
sh "s3cmd sync --reduced-redundancy --add-header 'Expires: Thu, 6 Feb 2020 00:00:00 GMT' _site/images/* s3://www.heathanderson.net/images/"
end
</code></pre>
<p>After placing the above in a <a href="https://github.com/handerson/heathanderson.net/blob/master/rakefile.rb">rakefile</a> all I have to do is run the following to publish a new post or deploy any other changes:</p>
<pre><code class="language-bash">
rake deploy
</code></pre>]]></content>
</entry>


<entry>
<title>Why Amazon S3?</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.heathanderson.net/2011/08/13/why-amazon-s3" />
<id>https://www.heathanderson.net/2011/08/13/why-amazon-s3</id>
<published>Sat, 13 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</published>
<author>
<name>Heath Anderson</name>
<uri>https://www.heathanderson.net/</uri>
</author>
<content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="https://www.heathanderson.net/"><![CDATA[<p>The main reason for switching to S3 as a host for this site was cost. This blog gets almost no traffic so I anticipate my monthly S3 bill to be less than $1 USD. That is pretty cheap. I was previously using a VPS from <a href="http://www.linode.com">Linode</a>. It was $19.99 a month. I love Linode, and next time I need a VPS I will go with them. But it was overkill for this blog. I was simply serving static HTML from Apache.</p>
<img class="shadow" src="/images/posts/s3calc.png" alt="Simple Monthly Calculator"/>
<p>Using Amazon's <a href="http://calculator.s3.amazonaws.com/calc5.html">Simple Monthly Calculator</a> I estimate that even if this site gets a couple orders of magnitude more popular, I'll still be paying less than $4.00 a month.</p>
<p>I also no longer have to worry about server security and server uptime. Those are two pretty big pluses.</p>]]></content>
</entry>


<entry>
<title>Using Amazon S3 for Hosting</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.heathanderson.net/2011/08/13/using-amazon-s3-for-hosting" />
<id>https://www.heathanderson.net/2011/08/13/using-amazon-s3-for-hosting</id>
<published>Sat, 13 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</published>
<author>
<name>Heath Anderson</name>
<uri>https://www.heathanderson.net/</uri>
</author>
<content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="https://www.heathanderson.net/"><![CDATA[<p>Earlier this year Amazon S3 was <a href="https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2011/02/17/Amazon-S3-Website-Features/">updated</a> to more easily support hosting static websites. The full <a href="http://docs.amazonwebservices.com/AmazonS3/latest/dev/index.html?WebsiteHosting.html">documentation</a> is online, but I'll give a quick overview of how it works here.</p>
<img class="shadow" src="/images/posts/create_bucket.png" alt="Create a bucket"/>
<p>The first step was to create a bucket. The only way I could get the DNS CNAME record (more on that in a minute) for my domain to actually point to the correct bucket was to name the bucket the same as the domain. I didn't see this mentioned anywhere in the documentation so perhaps I was doing something incorrectly.</p>
<img class="shadow" src="/images/posts/website_tab.png" alt="Website Tab"/>
<p>The new 'Website' tab what makes hosting a site possibility. All that needs to be done here is click the 'Enable' checkbox and tell S3 what the site's index document (usually index.html) and error document (usually 404.html) are. Also note the endpoint url--it is needed when setting up the DNS.</p>
<img class="shadow" src="/images/posts/edit_policy.png" alt="Edit Edit"/>
<p>Another thing that needed to be done is setting the policy so that others can actually view the site. This is found on the properties menu in the S3 management console for your website's bucket and go to the permissions tab. The 'Edit buck policy' button brings up a text area where I pasted the following (found in the <a href="http://docs.amazonwebservices.com/AmazonS3/latest/dev/index.html?WebsiteHosting.html">documentation</a>):</p>
<pre><code class="language-javascript">
{
"Version": "2008-10-17",
"Id": "",
"Statement": [
{
"Sid": "PublicReadGetObject",
"Effect": "Allow",
"Principal": {
"AWS": "*"
},
"Action": "s3:GetObject",
"Resource": "arn:aws:s3:::www.heathanderson.net/*"
}
]
}
</code></pre>
<p>After copying my site to the buck and testing the endpoint URL in my browser, I was ready to set up my domain to point to my new host.</p>
<img class="shadow" src="/images/posts/dns.png" alt="Edit DNS"/>
<p>Setting up the DNS was easy. All it takes is setting the root domain to forward to the www subdomain, and setting up a CNAME alias for the www subdomain to the endpoint from the 'Website' tab of the Amazon S3 management console.</p>
<p>The only problem that I had was when I initially named my bucket 'blogofheath'. I followed all the steps listed above, but when trying to visit the site from <a href="http://www.heathanderson.net">www.heathanderson.net</a> I kept getting an error. Apparently Amazon was to to serve a bucket named 'www.heathanderson.net' and since that bucket didn't exist things were not working. So I created a new bucket (renaming buckets isn't allowed), named it the same as my domain, and went through the same steps. Then it worked. Any ideas?</p>]]></content>
</entry>


<entry>
<title>Simple Search</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.heathanderson.net/2011/08/06/adding-search" />
<id>https://www.heathanderson.net/2011/08/06/adding-search</id>
<published>Sat, 06 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</published>
<author>
<name>Heath Anderson</name>
<uri>https://www.heathanderson.net/</uri>
</author>
<content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="https://www.heathanderson.net/"><![CDATA[<p>I often come across interesting ideas and tools that I have no current use for but seem like they may be useful someday, so I bookmark them and hope I will recall them when needed. That process is what led to the current implementation of site search located at the bottom of each page on this blog.</p>
<p>At some point I came across an <a href="http://googlewebmastercentral.blogspot.com/2008/08/make-your-404-pages-more-useful.html">article</a> on the the Google Webmaster Central Blog about <a href="http://www.google.com/support/webmasters/bin/answer.py?answer=136085">enhancing</a> a site's 404 page. I thought it was a pretty cool idea, and I'm <a href="/404.html">using</a> it on this site. The required code is very short:</p>
<pre><code class="language-javascript">
&lt;script type="text/javascript">
var GOOG_FIXURL_LANG = 'en';
var GOOG_FIXURL_SITE = 'http://www.example.com'
&lt;/script>
&lt;script type="text/javascript"
src="http://linkhelp.clients.google.com/tbproxy/lh/wm/fixurl.js">
&lt;/script>
</code></pre>
<p>The most interesting thing about it is that it adds a search form. It doesn't actually submit a form. It simply changes the current page's location to "http://www.google.com/search?q=site:www.heathanderson.net" (with the text from the text box appended) using JavaScript. This limits the Google search to (in this case) pages from my site. It is a really simple concept that I would like to think I would of eventually thought of (but probably wouldn't have). </p>
<p>When I needed a search for this site I decided to try this technique. So here it is, a simple search script:
<pre><code class="language-html">
&lt;script type="text/javascript">
function simpleSearch(form) {
var q = window.encodeURIComponent(form["q"].value);
var url = "http://www.google.com/search?q=site:www.heathanderson.net ";
url = url + q;window.location = url;
return false;
}
&lt;/script>
&lt;noscript>
You can search this site using <a href="http://www.google.com/search?q=site:www.heathanderson.net">Google</a>.
&lt;/noscript>
&lt;form onsubmit="return simpleSearch(this)" method="get" id="searchForm">
&lt;input type="text" size="40" name="q" placeholder="Search this site...">
&lt;input type="submit" value="Search">
&lt;/form>
</code></pre>
<p>I could have created the form element in JavaScript and appended it to the page, but that seemed more complicated than necessary. I also could have used an event handler instead of the inline onsubmit attribute, but again I point to the complexity. This way avoids most cross-browser pitfalls, and has the advantage of simplicity. I also added a link to Google inside a noscript tag for people that have JavaScript disabled.</p>]]></content>
</entry>


<entry>
<title>Another Blog Redesign</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.heathanderson.net/2011/08/05/another-blog-redesign" />
<id>https://www.heathanderson.net/2011/08/05/another-blog-redesign</id>
<published>Fri, 05 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</published>
<author>
<name>Heath Anderson</name>
<uri>https://www.heathanderson.net/</uri>
</author>
<content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="https://www.heathanderson.net/"><![CDATA[<p><img class="shadow" alt="HTML5 banner" src="http://www.heathanderson.net/images/posts/HTML5_sticker.png" />I've decided to change the design of the this blog once again. I've radically simplified the site. The side bar is gone. The comment section is gone. Pretty much all the JavaScript is gone (the exception being the search box at the bottom of each page). The site is now <a href="http://www.w3.org/html/logo/">HTML5</a>--no more XHTML.</p>
<p>I am still using <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a> to generate the HTML files of the site. I love the simplicity of it. I'm hosting the site on <a href="http://aws.amazon.com/s3/">Amazon S3</a>. It is fast, cheap and maintenance free. </p>
<p>I hope this new, streamlined version of my site will encourage me to post more. I guess we'll see.</p>]]></content>
</entry>


<entry>
<title>Using will_paginate and activerecord-sqlserver-adapter with SQL Server</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.heathanderson.net/2011/08/01/using-will_paginate-with-sql-server" />
<id>https://www.heathanderson.net/2011/08/01/using-will_paginate-with-sql-server</id>
<published>Mon, 01 Aug 2011 00:00:00 GMT</published>
<author>
<name>Heath Anderson</name>
<uri>https://www.heathanderson.net/</uri>
</author>
<content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="https://www.heathanderson.net/"><![CDATA[<p>Having Rails and Microsoft SQL Server communicate is much easier than it once was thanks to projects like <a href="https://github.com/rails-sqlserver/tiny_tds">TinyTDS</a>, but sometimes things still don't work exactly right. <a href="http://blacksnowmedia.com/">We</a> ran into an issue where pagination simply would not work. Below is what we came up with after some research.</p>
<p>This solution was based on the following:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="">http://alexle.net/archives/tag/mislav-will_paginate-sqlserver-2005</a>
<li><a href="http://www.sqlservercentral.com/articles/T-SQL/66030/">http://www.sqlservercentral.com/articles/T-SQL/66030/</a>
<li><a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/4871523/sql-server-2008-r2-pagination/4871591#4871591">http://stackoverflow.com/questions/4871523/sql-server-2008-r2-pagination/4871591#4871591</a>
<li><a href="https://gist.github.com/335683">https://gist.github.com/335683</a>
</ul>
<p>This patch was tested on an app using Rails 2.3.x and SQL Server Adapter 2.3.15.</p>
config/environment.rb
<pre><code class="language-ruby">
require "#{RAILS_ROOT}/lib/monkey_patch_sql2005_limit.rb"
</code></pre>
lib/monkey_patch_sql2005_limit.rb
<pre><code class="language-ruby">
# monkey-patching SQLServerAdapter to support SQL Server 2005-style pagination
# based on http://alexle.net/archives/tag/mislav-will_paginate-sqlserver-2005
# - http://alexle.net/archives/tag/mislav-will_paginate-sqlserver-2005
# - http://www.sqlservercentral.com/articles/T-SQL/66030/
# - http://stackoverflow.com/questions/4871523/sql-server-2008-r2-pagination/4871591#4871591
# - https://gist.github.com/335683
# produces paginated sql ( if set to 2 results per page) that looks like this:
#
# WITH cols AS (
#   SELECT ROW_NUMBER() OVER(ORDER BY training_types.id) as seq,
#     * FROM [training_types]
# )
# SELECT * FROM cols WHERE seq BETWEEN 1 AND 2 ORDER BY seq;
module ActiveRecord
module ConnectionAdapters
class SQLServerAdapter  < AbstractAdapter
def add_limit_offset!(sql, options)
if options[:limit].blank?
super
else
options[:offset] ||= 0
options[:limit] ||= 1000
table = sql.match(/FROM\s+\[(\w+)/i)[1]
options[:order] ||= "#{table}.id"
sql.sub!(/ORDER BY.*$/i, '')
sql.sub!(/SELECT/i, "WITH cols AS ( SELECT ROW_NUMBER() OVER(ORDER BY #{options[:order]}) as seq, ")
sql << ") SELECT * FROM cols WHERE seq BETWEEN #{options[:offset]+1} AND #{options[:offset]+options[:limit]} ORDER BY seq"
sql
end
end
end
end
end
</code></pre>]]></content>
</entry>


<entry>
<title>Welcome to the new blog</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.heathanderson.net/2010/09/06/welcome-to-the-new-blog" />
<id>https://www.heathanderson.net/2010/09/06/welcome-to-the-new-blog</id>
<published>Mon, 06 Sep 2010 00:00:00 GMT</published>
<author>
<name>Heath Anderson</name>
<uri>https://www.heathanderson.net/</uri>
</author>
<content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="https://www.heathanderson.net/"><![CDATA[<p>I've finally had time to move my personal blog off of Wordpress.com. Now it is just static HTML generated by <a href="http://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</a>. The new address is <a href="http://www.heathanderson.net">http://www.heathanderson.net</a>; http://www.blogofheath.com will redirect there.</p>
<p>I hope to posting *something* at least once a month. I know that doesn't sound like a lot, but I've had a blog for about a year and only have four previous posts. That is kind of pathetic. I'm planning on posting more than just code related stuff, so-- if programming doesn't interest you --maybe all hope of you reading future posts isn't lost.</p>
<p>What am I using to generate this site? Here is the list:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://github.com/mojombo/jekyll">Jekyll</a>
<li><a href="http://github.com/rfelix/jekyll_ext">jekyll_ext</a>
<li><a href="http://github.com/rfelix/my_jekyll_extensions">rfelix's plugins</a>
<li><a href="http://github.com/seaofclouds/tweet">tweet</a>
<li><a href="http://disqus.com/">Disqus</a>
<li><a href="http://swip.codylindley.com/DOMWindowDemo.html">DOMwindow</a>
<li><a href="http://themeforest.net/item/clean-blog/49983">Clean Blog</a> theme
<li><a href="http://www.flickr.com/badge.gne">Flickr Badge Generator</a>
</ul>
<p>I'm hosting this on <a href="http://linode.com">Linode</a>. Server side is the usual--Apache. I'm deploying using git's post receive hook. It is pretty sweet.</p>]]></content>
</entry>


<entry>
<title>Ruby on Rails Plugin: string_encryption</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.heathanderson.net/2009/11/23/ruby-on-rails-plugin-string_encryption" />
<id>https://www.heathanderson.net/2009/11/23/ruby-on-rails-plugin-string_encryption</id>
<published>Mon, 23 Nov 2009 00:00:00 GMT</published>
<author>
<name>Heath Anderson</name>
<uri>https://www.heathanderson.net/</uri>
</author>
<content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="https://www.heathanderson.net/"><![CDATA[<p>This is a very simple Ruby on Rails plugin that allows easy encryption of strings. For the sake of simplicity there no customization. The only cipher used is 'des-ede3-cbc' (Triple DES using Cipher Block Chaining) . See my <a href="http://blogofheath.com/2009/09/25/ruby-string-encryption/">post </a> on encrypting/decrypting a string with Ruby for more information. First install the plugin:</p>
<pre><code class="language-ruby">
script/plugin install git://github.com/handerson/string_encryption.git
</code></pre>
<p>Next we need to add an encryption key as the constant @ENV['STRING_ENCRYPTION_KEY']@. To do this just run</p>
<pre><code class="language-ruby">
script/generate encryption_key
</code></pre>
<p>or you could set </p>
<pre><code class="language-ruby">
ENV['STRING_ENCRYPTION_KEY'] = "somekey"
</code></pre>
<p>where "somekey" is your key in environment.rb.</p>
<p>Now encryption/decryption is easy.</p>
<h3>Encryption:</h3>
<pre><code class="language-ruby">
"Test".encrypt  #=> "NDFkZTc5NDEyNTg1MzdiZPzBrxZz5aoN%0A"
</code></pre>
<h3>Decryption:</h3>
<pre><code class="language-ruby">
"NDFkZTc5NDEyNTg1MzdiZPzBrxZz5aoN%0A".decrypt  #=> "Test"
</code></pre>
<p>Code at Github:<br/>
<a href="http://github.com/handerson/string_encryption">http://github.com/handerson/string_encryption</a></p>]]></content>
</entry>


<entry>
<title>Initialization Vector Length in MRI Ruby versus JRuby</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.heathanderson.net/2009/09/27/initialization-vector-length-in-mri-ruby-versus-jruby" />
<id>https://www.heathanderson.net/2009/09/27/initialization-vector-length-in-mri-ruby-versus-jruby</id>
<published>Sun, 27 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</published>
<author>
<name>Heath Anderson</name>
<uri>https://www.heathanderson.net/</uri>
</author>
<content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="https://www.heathanderson.net/"><![CDATA[<p>When using OpenSSL encryption in standard Ruby, the length of an initialization vector (IV) can apparently be as large as you want it to be as long as it is at least the minimum size. This is odd. This can also cause trouble when switching over to JRuby. JRuby appear to be much pickier about IV length.</p>
<p>This works in MRI but not in JRuby:</p>
<pre><code class="language-ruby">
unencrypted_data = "test"
des = OpenSSL::Cipher::Cipher.new("des-ede3-cbc")
des.encrypt
des.key = '0123456789abcdef01234567890'
des.iv = "ed87acdcca419954edccb736f7dc77a74f5ac8dfe3861c3d5f77248e21592131a5423d63ff91f07956ce1aa386f8359931b5" # 100 characters
encrypted_data = des.update(unencrypted_data) + des.final
puts encrypted_data
</code></pre>
<p>JRuby gives you this very helpful message:<br/>
@ruby_string_encryption.rb:27:in `encrypt': No message available (OpenSSL::Cipher::CipherError)<br/>
from ruby_string_encryption.rb:37@</p>
<p>Change the IV to 8 characters and everything works fine.</p>
<p><em>Update 10/14/2009</em> The code that I originally posted was incorrect. I have updated it. Also I opened a <a href="http://jira.codehaus.org/browse/JRUBY-4012">ticket </a>for this issue. </p>
<p>If you are looking for what size an initialization vector should be check out my post on <a href="http://www.heathanderson.net/2009/09/25/ruby-string-encryption/">encrypting a string with Ruby</a>.</p>]]></content>
</entry>


<entry>
<title>Ruby String Encryption</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.heathanderson.net/2009/09/25/ruby-string-encryption" />
<id>https://www.heathanderson.net/2009/09/25/ruby-string-encryption</id>
<published>Fri, 25 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</published>
<author>
<name>Heath Anderson</name>
<uri>https://www.heathanderson.net/</uri>
</author>
<content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="https://www.heathanderson.net/"><![CDATA[<p>Encrypting a string is fairly easy in Ruby. All you need to do is @require 'openssl'@. For this example I am using the 'des-ede3-cbc' (<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Triple_des">Triple DES</a> using <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Block_cipher_modes_of_operation">Cipher Block Chaining</a>) cipher. Most--if not all--of the ciphers listed on <a href="http://www.openssl.org/docs/apps/enc.html">OpenSSL.org</a> as supported ciphers should work as well. </p>
<p>Triple DES requires a 24-byte key, with Ruby this means a string with 24 characters. We are also required to provide an <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Initialization_vector">initialization vector</a> (IV). The IV is usually the same size as the block size of the cipher you are using (so says Wikipedia, so say we all). In our case this means an IV of 64-bits, or 8-bytes, or an 8 character Ruby String. If we randomize our IV and include it with our encrypted string then we can ensure that our encrypted data never looks the same even when we encrypt the same string multiple times.</p>
<pre><code class="language-ruby">
require 'openssl'
KEY = '0123456789abcdef01234567890' # 24 characters
string = "encrypt this"
des = OpenSSL::Cipher::Cipher.new("des-ede3-cbc")
des.encrypt # this tells OpenSSL what mode to operate in, here we want to encrypt data
des.iv = iv = '01234567' # 8 characters, hard-coded for now
data = des.update(string) + des.final
data = iv + data # this way when we randomize our IV it will be available when we need to decrypt the data
puts data
</code></pre>
<p>This should output some crazy string. This isn't the friendliest way to send data, so lets do something about that. The easiest thing to do is Base 64 encode the data, and maybe <a href="http://snippets.dzone.com/posts/show/1260">URI escape</a> it for good measure.</p>
<pre><code class="language-ruby">
# be sure to put the following at the top of your code:
# require "base64"
# require 'uri'
# after 'the puts data' in the snippet above do the following:
data = Base64.encode64(data)
data = URI.escape(data, Regexp.new("[^#{URI::PATTERN::UNRESERVED}]"))
puts data
</code></pre>
<p>This should give you the much nicer @MDEyMzQ1Njd6jzSlS73fKSAdqYgRiJie%0A@.</p>
<p>Decryption is similarly easy.</p>
<pre><code class="language-ruby">
des = OpenSSL::Cipher::Cipher.new("des-ede3-cbc")
des.decrypt
des.key = KEY
encrypted_data = URI.unescape(data)
encrypted_data = Base64.decode64(data)
des.iv =  encrypted_data.slice!(0,8) #This gives us our iv back and removes it from the encrypted data
decrypted = des.update(encrypted_data) + des.final
puts decrypted
</code></pre>
<p>If you are using Rails or have access to ActiveSupport <a href="http://api.rubyonrails.org/classes/ActiveSupport/SecureRandom.html">ActiveSupport::SecureRandom</a> is a great way to generate your key and IV. Also be sure to check out <a href="http://api.rubyonrails.org/classes/ActiveSupport/MessageEncryptor.html">ActiveSupport::MessageEncryptor</a> and my <a href="http://github.com/handerson/string_encryption">string_encryption</a> plugin. I'll probably do a writeup on the string_encryption plugin sometime next week.</p>]]></content>
</entry>


<entry>
<title>Ruby on Rails Plugin: data_migration</title>
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://www.heathanderson.net/2009/09/22/ruby-on-rails-plugin-data_migration" />
<id>https://www.heathanderson.net/2009/09/22/ruby-on-rails-plugin-data_migration</id>
<published>Tue, 22 Sep 2009 00:00:00 GMT</published>
<author>
<name>Heath Anderson</name>
<uri>https://www.heathanderson.net/</uri>
</author>
<content type="html" xml:lang="en" xml:base="https://www.heathanderson.net/"><![CDATA[<p>data_migration allows you to separate data you need to load from your normal database migrations in a minimal way. While developing the new version of our flagship site, <a href="http://www.knetwit.com">Knetwit</a>, we decided we needed to separate our data migrations (initial settings and the like) from our structural migrations. We decided the easiest way to do this was to modify the existing Rails migration to allow for a new data migration. So we did.</p>
<h3>Install Plugin</h3>
<pre><code class="language-ruby">
script/plugin install git://github.com/handerson/data_migration.git
</code></pre>
<h3>Generate Migration</h3>
<pre><code class="language-ruby">
script/generate data_migration BlockedDomains
</code></pre>
<pre><code class="language-ruby">
exists  db/data
create  db/data/20090915161242_settings.rb[/sourcecode]
</code></pre>
<p>db/data/20090915161242_settings.rb:</p>
<pre><code class="language-ruby">
class BlockedDomains &lt; ActiveRecord::Migration
def self.up
end
end
</code></pre>
<p>Add your data:</p>
<pre><code class="language-ruby">
def self.up
BlockedEmailDomain.create(:domain => "mailinator.com")
BlockedEmailDomain.create(:domain => "spamherelots.com")
BlockedEmailDomain.create(:domain => "disposeamail.com")
end
</code></pre>
<h3>Run Migration</h3>
<pre><code class="language-ruby">
rake db:data:migrate
</code></pre>
<pre><code class="language-ruby">
==  BlockedDomains: migrating ===========================================================
==  BlockedDomains: migrated (0.0020s) ==================================================
</code></pre>
<p>db:data:migrate adds the data migration version number to the 'schema_migrations' table so it will not be ran again.</p>
<p>Code at Github:<br/>
<a href="http://github.com/handerson/data_migration">http://github.com/handerson/data_migration</a></p>]]></content>
</entry>

</feed>